const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the cause of death in shaken baby syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiac arrythmia","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory paralysis","bool":false},{"option":"Brain death","bool":true},{"option":"Sepsis","bool":false},{"option":"Pontine hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which part of the kidney has the lowest osmolality?","answers":[{"option":"Descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of the loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle near distal tubule","bool":true}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Glucose is completely reabsorbed by the time filtrate reaches which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":true},{"option":"Distal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical collecting tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary collecting tubule","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the flow of plasma per minute into the Bowman's capsule called?","answers":[{"option":"Renal excretion rate","bool":false},{"option":"Reabsorption rate","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular filtration rate","bool":true},{"option":"Volume of distribution","bool":false},{"option":"Clearance","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the treatment of severe hypokalemia?","answers":[{"option":"Oral tablets with slow release","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"IV potassium in dextrose","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphate binder","bool":false},{"option":"IV potassium in normal saline","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which electrocardiogram (ECG) finding is common in hypokalemia?","answers":[{"option":"P wave flattening","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperacute T waves","bool":false},{"option":"U waves","bool":true},{"option":"ST segment elevation","bool":false},{"option":"Wide QRS complex","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following structures is present entirely in the kidney cortex?","answers":[{"option":"Pyramid","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulus","bool":true},{"option":"Collecting tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Calyx","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of henle","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"How does the medulla maintain a hyperosmolar gradient?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium chloride co-transporter","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial sodium channels","bool":false},{"option":"Urea reabsorption through the proximal tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Action of Na/K/Cl co-transporter","bool":true},{"option":"Absorption of water","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which one of these is not a type of proteinuria?","answers":[{"option":"Glomerular","bool":false},{"option":"Tubular","bool":false},{"option":"Anatomical","bool":true},{"option":"Overflow","bool":false},{"option":"Post-renal","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of nephrotic syndrome in children?","answers":[{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":true},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What penal code does rape come under?","answers":[{"option":"300 PPC","bool":false},{"option":"381 PPC","bool":false},{"option":"370 PPC","bool":false},{"option":"350 PPC","bool":false},{"option":"376 PPC","bool":true}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A patient presents with suprapubic pain, dysuria, and frequency of urination. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":true},{"option":"Bladder carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Perinephric abscess","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the term used for someone who practices sodomy?","answers":[{"option":"Heterosexual","bool":false},{"option":"Catamite","bool":false},{"option":"Sodomite","bool":true},{"option":"Homosexual","bool":false},{"option":"Pervert","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the basic requirement for the examination of a rape victim?","answers":[{"option":"Privacy","bool":false},{"option":"Oral consent","bool":false},{"option":"Male doctor","bool":false},{"option":"Written consent","bool":true},{"option":"Two witnesses","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"When can a man's intercourse with his wife be classified as rape?","answers":[{"option":"Intercourse while separated","bool":false},{"option":"Man's age below 18","bool":false},{"option":"Wife's age under 18 years","bool":false},{"option":"Man's age above 18","bool":false},{"option":"Wife's age under 12 years","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of drug-induced interstitial nephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Methotrexate","bool":false},{"option":"Vancomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":true},{"option":"Allopurinol","bool":false},{"option":"Moxifloxacin","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Where does the middle portion of the ureter drain into?","answers":[{"option":"External iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Preaortic nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Common iliac nodes","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these is an absolute indication for surgery in benign prostatic hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"Repeated hematuria","bool":false},{"option":"Recurrent urinary tract infections (UTIs)","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder stones","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary retention unresponsive to medical therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Severe symptoms","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the color code for harmful (risk) waste without sharps?","answers":[{"option":"Blue","bool":true},{"option":"Black","bool":false},{"option":"Red","bool":false},{"option":"Yellow","bool":false},{"option":"White","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is e-waste?","answers":[{"option":"Electronics","bool":true},{"option":"Chemicals","bool":false},{"option":"Electricity","bool":false},{"option":"Ecological waste","bool":false},{"option":"Environmental friendly","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these can not be used to differentiate pre-renal from renal failure?","answers":[{"option":"Urine osmolality","bool":false},{"option":"Fractional excretion of sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Urine output","bool":true},{"option":"Specific gravity of urine","bool":false},{"option":"Urine sodium","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these statements about acetazolamide is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"It leads to hypokalemia","bool":false},{"option":"It can be used for chronic simple glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"It works on the Na/H pump","bool":true},{"option":"It can be used for acute on chronic glaucoma","bool":false},{"option":"It can lead to metabolic acidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which diuretic can be used for recurrent calcium stones?","answers":[{"option":"Carbonic anhydrase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Loop diuretic","bool":false},{"option":"Osmotic diuretic","bool":false},{"option":"Thiazide diuretic","bool":true},{"option":"ADH antagonist","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these stones is commonly formed as a result of infection?","answers":[{"option":"Cystine","bool":false},{"option":"Struvite","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium phosphate","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A patient presents with loin pain and hematuria. What is the first line of investigation?","answers":[{"option":"CT scan","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray KUB","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray abdomen","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":true},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which type of fractures are seen with child abuse?","answers":[{"option":"Spalding fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Pathologic fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Buckle fractures","bool":false},{"option":"Nobbing fracture","bool":true},{"option":"Greenstick fractures","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A boy was riding his bicycle when he fell on his stomach. If the point of impact is the epigastric region, which organ is most likely to be ruptured?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreas","bool":true},{"option":"Colon","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"At which week, levels of beta-human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG) peak at?","answers":[{"option":"12 to 15 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"8 to 10 weeks","bool":true},{"option":"5 to 6 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"20 to 22 weeks","bool":false},{"option":"17 to 19 weeks","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which diuretic, given for cardiac problems, can potentially cause orthostatic hypotension?","answers":[{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":true},{"option":"Chlorthalidone","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrochlorothiazide","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common infection that can cause rupture of the spleen from a minor trauma?","answers":[{"option":"Leishmaniasis","bool":false},{"option":"Malaria","bool":true},{"option":"Dengue fever","bool":false},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Typhoid","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A 40-year-old man has had increasing lower extremity edema for the past three weeks. On examination, his blood pressure (BP) is 135/90 mmHg and pitting edema up till his knees. Laboratory results show serum creatinine level of 1.2 mg/dl and urea nitrogen of 16 mg/dl. 24-hour urine protein of 7.4 grams. Serum ASO, ANA, HIV, and ANCA are negative. Complement levels are also normal. On renal biopsy, there is a diffuse uniform thickening of the glomerular basement membranes. Immunofluorescence shows granular IgG and C3 basement membrane deposits. In the given scenario, electron microscopy would most likely reveal which finding?","answers":[{"option":"Fusion of podocyte foot processes","bool":false},{"option":"Mesangial IgG and C3 electron dense deposits","bool":false},{"option":"No abnormality","bool":false},{"option":"Sub-endothelial electron dense deposits with duplication of basement membranes","bool":false},{"option":"Sub-epithelial IgG and C3 deposits electron dense deposits","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Poor handling of food in canteens predisposes to food poisoning from which infectious agent?","answers":[{"option":"Vibrio cholerae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Salmonella typhi","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium botulinum","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium perfringes","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What are the most commonly fractured ribs?","answers":[{"option":"4th-8th ribs","bool":true},{"option":"1st-2nd ribs","bool":false},{"option":"4th-6th ribs","bool":false},{"option":"3rd-8th ribs","bool":false},{"option":"2nd-7th ribs","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common site of rupture of the heart?","answers":[{"option":"Right side with apex","bool":false},{"option":"Left side with base","bool":false},{"option":"Right side with base","bool":false},{"option":"Atria","bool":false},{"option":"Left side with apex","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these substances increases gastric excitability?","answers":[{"option":"Acetylcholine","bool":true},{"option":"Serotonin","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":false},{"option":"Norepinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Cholecystokinin","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of chronic kidney disease?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetes","bool":true},{"option":"Drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Age","bool":false},{"option":"Vasculitis","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common cause of nephritic syndrome in children?","answers":[{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Lupus nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Post streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the correct statement regarding polycystic kidney disease in children?","answers":[{"option":"Gene on chromosome 16","bool":false},{"option":"Vascular aneurysms","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal dominant inheritence","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive inheritance","bool":true},{"option":"Polycystin defect","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which cells will be seen upon kidney biopsy in a patient with post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leukocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Epitheloid cells","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cells","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"In a patient with stage T1 prostatic carcinoma, what is the treatment of choice?","answers":[{"option":"Radiotherapy plus surgery","bool":false},{"option":"Chemotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery plus radiotherapy and chemotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Transurethral resection of prostate","bool":false},{"option":"Radical prostectomy","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these conditions is easily confused with renal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Wilm's tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Xanthogranulomatous pyelonephritis","bool":true}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these risk factors does not predispose to pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Stones","bool":false},{"option":"Autonomic neuropathy","bool":true},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Renal tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnancy","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the best treatment for benign prostatic hyperplasia with lower urinary tract symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Aromatase inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"5 alpha reductase inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Transurethral resection of prostate","bool":true},{"option":"Alpha 1 antagonists","bool":false},{"option":"Radical prostectomy","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the treatment of choice for posterior urethral valves?","answers":[{"option":"Expectant management","bool":false},{"option":"Radiotherapy","bool":false},{"option":"Transurethral resection","bool":true},{"option":"Cystostomy and catheter placement","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 1 antagonist","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"The term 'pyonephrosis' is used to describe which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Total obstruction of urine","bool":false},{"option":"Collecion of pus in Gerota's fascia","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophilic inflammation of the interstitium","bool":false},{"option":"Supparative inflammation","bool":true},{"option":"Fatty casts in urine","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following terms is consistent with ischemic tubular necrosis of kidneys?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophils in urine","bool":false},{"option":"Confluent necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Patchy necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Polyuria","bool":false},{"option":"Patchy supparation","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these is accurate about simple kidney cysts?","answers":[{"option":"Commonly symptomatic","bool":false},{"option":"Echoic masses","bool":false},{"option":"Cuboidal epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"Septations","bool":false},{"option":"Size greater than 5 cm","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these cystic disorders is characterized by cysts at the corticomedullar junction?","answers":[{"option":"Autosomal dominant polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive polycystic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Multicystic renal dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary sponge kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Adult onset medullary cystic disease","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these features regarding congenital cystic kidney disease is false?","answers":[{"option":"Symptoms start from childhood","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral","bool":false},{"option":"Present since birth","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive mode of inheritence","bool":false},{"option":"Unilateral","bool":true}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these features is not a part of adult-onset polycystic kidney disease?","answers":[{"option":"Presents at puberty","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral involvement","bool":false},{"option":"Hematuria","bool":false},{"option":"Autosomal recessive inheritence","bool":true},{"option":"Presents in adulthood","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Sub-epithelial humps on electron microscopy of glomerulus are characteristic of?","answers":[{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common presentation of renal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Costovertebral pain","bool":false},{"option":"Burning micturition","bool":false},{"option":"Palpable mass","bool":false},{"option":"Painless hematuria","bool":true},{"option":"Weight loss","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A glomerular disease is strongly associated with hepatitis B and presents as nephrotic syndrome. Which of these pathologic features is consistent with this disease?","answers":[{"option":"Sub-epithelial humps on electron microscopy","bool":false},{"option":"No visible pathologic change","bool":false},{"option":"Granular deposits on immunofluorescence","bool":false},{"option":"Spike and dome appearance on electron microscopy","bool":true},{"option":"Linear deposits on immunofluorescence","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these drugs is strongly nephrotoxic?","answers":[{"option":"Fluoroquinolones","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false},{"option":"Aminoglycosides","bool":true},{"option":"Tetracyclines","bool":false},{"option":"Meropenem","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following regions of nephrons is most affected in toxin-mediated acute tubular necrosis?","answers":[{"option":"Ascending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Descending limb of loop of Henle","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":true}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these physiologic derangements can be seen in hemodynamic instability?","answers":[{"option":"Low urine osmolality","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased filtration fraction","bool":false},{"option":"Increased renal plasma flow","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased GFR","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Anatomical waste should be disposed off in which color-coded bag?","answers":[{"option":"Yellow","bool":true},{"option":"Red","bool":false},{"option":"Blue","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false},{"option":"White","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the drug of choice for acute pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Trimethoprim","bool":false},{"option":"Aminoglycoside","bool":false},{"option":"Fluoroquinolone","bool":true},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrofurantoin","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these stones are radiolucent?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":false},{"option":"Cystine","bool":false},{"option":"Struvite","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common type of kidney stone?","answers":[{"option":"Xanthine","bool":false},{"option":"Struvite","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium phosphate","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these diseases resembles IgA nephropathy?","answers":[{"option":"Henoch-Schonlein purpura","bool":true},{"option":"Wegener's granulomatosis","bool":false},{"option":"Giant cell arteritis","bool":false},{"option":"Churg-Strauss syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Polyarteritis nodosa","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these virulence factors is most important for urinary tract infection by E coli?","answers":[{"option":"Pili","bool":true},{"option":"Flagella","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Lipopolysaccharide","bool":false},{"option":"IgA protease","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these glomerular diseases is characterized by the 'tram-track' appearance of the glomerular basement membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomeurlonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common site of metastasis for renal cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Lungs","bool":true},{"option":"Breast","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Colon","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common kidney tumor in children?","answers":[{"option":"Nephroblastoma","bool":true},{"option":"Transitional cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Renal cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Angiomyolipoma","bool":false},{"option":"Hamartoma","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these components determines oncotic pressure in the glomerular capillaries?","answers":[{"option":"Plasma proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Water","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":false},{"option":"Electrolytes","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these disorders display hypocomplementemia?","answers":[{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these is classified as a sexual perversion?","answers":[{"option":"Lesbianism","bool":false},{"option":"Bestiality","bool":false},{"option":"Sadism","bool":true},{"option":"Sodomy","bool":false},{"option":"Rape","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of these statements is true regarding minimal change disease?","answers":[{"option":"It only occurs in childhood","bool":false},{"option":"It can occur at all ages","bool":true},{"option":"It manifests as nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"It does not respond well to steroids","bool":false},{"option":"It is characterized by sub-epithelial humps","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Calculate the net filtration pressure if the value of capillary pressure is 40 mm H2O, the value of colloid pressure in the capillary is 30 mm H2O, and the value of capsule pressure is 10 mm H20.","answers":[{"option":"20 mm H2O","bool":false},{"option":"5 mm H2O","bool":false},{"option":"10 mm H2O","bool":false},{"option":"0 mm H2O","bool":true},{"option":"15 mm H2O","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"How much is the total amount of cardiac output to the renal system?","answers":[{"option":"25%","bool":true},{"option":"10%","bool":false},{"option":"15%","bool":false},{"option":"50%","bool":false},{"option":"30%","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following injuries causes a gutter wound?","answers":[{"option":"Sharp weapon","bool":false},{"option":"Blunt weapon","bool":false},{"option":"Serrated edge weapon","bool":false},{"option":"Firearm injury","bool":true},{"option":"Thermal injury","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the usual clinical presentation of Goodpasture syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Transient proteinuria is the clinical presentation of which of the following pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Congestive heart failure","bool":true},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which is the most common site of staghorn calculus?","answers":[{"option":"Renal pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvicalyceal system","bool":true},{"option":"Ureteropelvic junction","bool":false},{"option":"Ureterovesical junction","bool":false},{"option":"Renal pyramids","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A female athlete presented to the emergency department with complaints of abdominal cramps and vomiting after running for miles. Upon examination, she looked dehydrated and was losing consciousness. What is the probable reason behind her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Increase in total body chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in total body sodium","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in total body potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in total body calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Increase in total body phosphate","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A woman with a history of lupus is found to have 2.3 grams of protein in her urine each day. In the investigation, wire looping of the capillaries is found on light microscopy. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse proliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common radiopaque renal stone?","answers":[{"option":"Uric acid stone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate stone","bool":true},{"option":"Cystine stone","bool":false},{"option":"Struvite stone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium phosphate stone","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following is the most common radiolucent renal stone?","answers":[{"option":"Ammonium magnesium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Cystine stone","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid stone","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following conditions is characterized by hypokalemia with normal blood pressure?","answers":[{"option":"Cushing syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Liddle syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Conn syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Bartter syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Batter syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"An autopsy is conducted on a person who passed away from a stroke. Postmortem caloricity is observed in this body. Which of the following may be the reason for the rise in temperature?","answers":[{"option":"Pontine hemorrhage","bool":true},{"option":"Arsenic poisoning","bool":false},{"option":"Subdural hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Extradural hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Hypovolemic shock","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which one of the following is contraindicated in intravenous pyelography?","answers":[{"option":"Cephalosporin","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin","bool":false},{"option":"Dapagliflozin","bool":false},{"option":"Metformin","bool":true},{"option":"Sulfonylureas","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A female patient presents to the clinic with a history of severe joint pain and a rash on her face in the shape of a butterfly that involves the bridges of the nose. She also has periorbital edema and the urine sample shows hematuria. What is the most likely cause of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Poststreptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Infective endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE)","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A female patient presents to the clinic with a history of severe joint pain and a rash on her face in the shape of a butterfly that involves the bridges of the nose. She also has periorbital edema and the urine sample shows hematuria. What is the most likely diagnosis of her condition?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelial cell injury","bool":false},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Urolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":true}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the role of anti-diuretic hormone in the human body?","answers":[{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of potassium","bool":false},{"option":"Helps regulate water balance in the body","bool":true},{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of sodium","bool":false},{"option":"Helps regulate absorption of chloride","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A patient presents to the outpatient department with recurrent urinary tract infection and flank pain. Upon investigation, envelope-shaped crystals are found deposited in the kidney. Which of the following is the composition of the crystals?","answers":[{"option":"Cystine","bool":false},{"option":"Uric acid","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium oxalate","bool":true},{"option":"Struvite","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following is the least likely cause of acute pyelonephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Chemotherapeutic agents","bool":false},{"option":"Inguinal hernia","bool":true},{"option":"Circulatory shock","bool":false},{"option":"Antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Radiocontrast material","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following morphological change is characteristically seen in minimal change disease?","answers":[{"option":"Thickened glomerular membranes with a \"tram-track\" appearance","bool":false},{"option":"Normal basement membrane with fusion of foot process","bool":true},{"option":"Sclerosis of particular segments of some glomeruli","bool":false},{"option":"Thickened glomerular membranes with \"spike and dome\" epithelial deposits","bool":false},{"option":"Crescent-shape seen in the Bowman space of glomeruli","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following statement is true regarding contrecoup injury?","answers":[{"option":"It results in pontine hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Injury to the chest","bool":false},{"option":"Lung is always affected","bool":false},{"option":"It is not related to traumatic subarachnoid hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Injury to the opposite direction of a moving head","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following drugs is least likely to cause hyperkalemia?","answers":[{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"ACE inhibitors","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":true},{"option":"Aldactone","bool":false},{"option":"Cyclosporine","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following does not cause hyperkalemia?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Dextrose water","bool":false},{"option":"Furosemide","bool":true},{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following is a characteristic finding of nephritic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Polyuria","bool":false},{"option":"Proteinuria","bool":false},{"option":"Hematuria","bool":true},{"option":"Hypotension","bool":false},{"option":"Lipiduria","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the amount of substance going into the tubules termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Oncotic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Osmotic pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Extrastitial load","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial load","bool":false},{"option":"Tubular load","bool":true}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following antibodies are found in focal segmental glomerulosclerosis?","answers":[{"option":"IgD and C3","bool":false},{"option":"IgG and C3","bool":false},{"option":"IgA and C3","bool":false},{"option":"IgM and C3","bool":true},{"option":"IgE and C3","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"What is the most common complication of a child with nephrotic syndrome?","answers":[{"option":"Protein malnutrition","bool":false},{"option":"Deep vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Renal vein thrombosis","bool":false},{"option":"Infections","bool":true},{"option":"Vitamin D deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"Which of the following diseases frequently presents with hematuria?","answers":[{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetic nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false},{"option":"Urolithiasis","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2017","question":"A 9-year-old boy is brought to the clinic with complaints of cola-colored urine. He has a past history of being treated for a sore throat infection 3 weeks ago. His blood pressure is 145/95 mmHg. Urinalysis reveals red cell casts. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Goodpasture's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":true},{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous glomerulopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Alport syndrome","bool":false}]}]
export default arr